bbbs.org 2015-12-05

# Privacy - Big Brothers Big Sisters

## Privacy Notice Effective Date: Jan. 1, 2015

We at Big Brothers Big Sisters of America (“BBBS”) respect your concerns about privacy and value the trust you have placed in us. This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect, how we may use that information, and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. In addition, we describe the choices you can make about how we use the information you provide to us. We tell you how you can update your contact information, remove your name from our mailing list, or answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices.

What types of information does BBBS collect and use about me and how does BBBS use the information?

We collect and use information about you to communicate with you about our products, services, promotions, programs and events, and to customize our communications in those areas. We also collect information to improve your website experience, enroll Big Brothers and Big Sisters and children and youth; enable you to make donations to BBBS, enable contact with BBBS alumni, and enable you to stay informed on legislative issues important to BBBS. Here are the ways we obtain information about you and the types of information we obtain. We also tell you how we use the information.

**Register for Our Newsletter.** When you ask us to send you our newsletter, you provide us with your email address so we can fulfill your request.

**Purchases.** When you order or purchase a BBBS product, you may choose to give us contact and payment information (such as credit card information) so we may process your order. When you pay for a BBBS product using a credit card, we use your credit card information only to fulfill your order and for other internal purposes.

**Contact Us Link.** If you contact us via our website, we may ask you for information such as your name, address and email address so we can respond to your questions or comments. Unless you consent, we do not retain this information except to respond to your inquiries.

**Website.** Like many organizations, we use cookies and log files on our website. Cookies are small text files that websites often store on the computer hard drives of visitors to their sites. A cookie contains a unique code, which is used to recognize your computer when a user of your computer returns to a website that was visited previously. Log files are small text files that websites automatically create when a user visits a site. We use cookies and log files to enhance the online experience of our visitors and to better understand how our site is used. Cookies and log files may tell us, for example, whether you have visited our site before or whether you are a new visitor.

The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Remember, though, without cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website features, such as participating in online games and sweepstakes.

**Enrollment.** When you enroll online to become a Big or Little, you give us your name, email address and phone number. If you are under 13 years old, we ask you to have your parent or guardian enroll you, or you may call your local agency directly.

**Special Offers and Instant Coupons.** From time to time, we may offer you discounts and rewards provided by our supporters. When you choose to download any special offers or instant coupons from our websites, we do not collect any personal information about you.

**eCards.** You may ask us to send an eCard on your behalf. We do not use any personal information you provide in connection with sending an eCard except to send the eCard.

**Participate in Contests and Sweepstakes.** When you sign up to participate in one of our contests or sweepstakes, you may provide us with information such as your name or email address. We may use the information to enter you in the contest or sweepstakes and contact you if you win. Also, unless you previously asked us not to send you our newsletter, we will add your email address to our newsletter list. If you do not want to receive information about BBBS, you may choose not to participate in our contests and sweepstakes.

**Donations.** You also give us contact information and credit card or checking information so we can process your donation. We use this information for that purpose and to customize our communication with you. Big Brothers Big Sisters of America will not share or sell a donor's personal information with anyone else, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations.

**Other Ways We May Use Information to Provide Services.** You may provide us with survey information to help us learn more about your preferences. We maintain information you provide to us in our database to provide you with the information, goods or services you have requested.

Does BBBS share the information it obtains about me with third parties?

BBBS does not share personal information about you with any third parties for their own marketing purposes. We do share this information with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf who may have their own privacy policies that may apply, but these service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. We also may disclose information about you to other members of the BBBS family (such as our local agencies, which may have their own privacy policies) or to sponsorship partners solely with respect to tracking and enhancing campaigns in furtherance of our mission and as required by law.

How does BBBS protect personal information?

The security of personal information is a high priority for us. We maintain online safeguards to protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration and destruction of the personal information in our possession. To protect the security of your credit card information, we use the industry standard for Internet security -- Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. This Internet encryption standard scrambles data as it travels from your computer to our server. You’ll know that you’re in a secure area of our website when the “http” portion of the BBBS website address in your browser changes to “https.” The “s” stands for “secure.”

How does BBBS update its Privacy Notice?

BBBS’s products, services, promotions and programs will change over time. This Privacy Notice will be updated periodically to reflect those changes and corresponding changes in our information practices. Whenever we revise this Privacy Notice, we will change the date on the notice to indicate when the revisions were made. We reserve the right to change our information practices and the terms of this Privacy Notice, and to apply the changed practices to all information we have about you.

Does the BBBS website contain links to other websites?

The BBBS website may contain links to other websites that operate independently of BBBS and are not under our control. We provide links to those sites solely for your convenience and information. Those sites have their own privacy notices, which we suggest you review if you visit any linked sites. BBBS is not responsible for information that is provided by those sites or for any other use of the sites.

How can I update my contact information?

Please email us to indicate that you would want to change the contact information we have for you. Please email us from the email address we would have on file so we can verify ownership.

Email us at [bigbrothersbigsisters@bbbs.org](mailto:bigbrothersbigsisters@bbbs.org).

Will I receive email from BBBS?

We will send you email only if you have provided us with your email address and have asked us to communicate with you this way.

What if I prefer not to receive communications from BBBS?

Please email us to indicate that you would like to unsubscribe from our mailings. Please email us from the email address we would have on file so we can verify ownership.

Email us at [bigbrothersbigsisters@bbbs.org](mailto:bigbrothersbigsisters@bbbs.org).

If you have any questions about BBBS’s privacy practices, click here.

99997.026302 NEW_YORK 177259v2

DATED: Jan. 1, 2015
